Arya Nair +91 98202 40197

arya.bnair411@gmail.com LinkedIn

With over 13 years of experience in Marketing, I am highly skilled in branding, communications, and digital marketing initiatives for global clients. My impressive track record demonstrates my ability to develop engaging brand and marketing collaterals for both internal and external audiences in the Consulting, Finance, and Technology sectors. I excel at strategizing, administering, and executing all marketing deliverables, including Board presentations and pitch decks. My passion for Marketing Automation and my talent for maintaining effective relationships with stakeholders make me the ideal candidate to take the lead on marketing mandates from conception to deployment.

Experience

Cogitate Technology Solutions, Mumbai

Communication Specialist | From May 2023

- ✓ Develop and execute communication plans to increase brand awareness and engagement
- ✓ Manage social media platforms, create engaging content, and grow online presence
- ✓ Manage all internal and external communication, collaborate with cross-functional teams for consistent messaging, monitor metrics, and provide data-driven recommendations for improvement
- ✓ Support event planning and coordination, develop webinar content, and conduct market research for communication trends and potential business opportunities
- Responsible for UI/UX for company's product platform to provide seamless customer experience for our insurance carrier clients, MGAs & Agency management systems in USA

Link Intime India, Mumbai

Marketing Manager | April 2022 to May 2023

- ✓ Led a team of 4 to establish Link Intime's presence across all channels and developed comprehensive communication strategies for their social media, while also heading the Media Planning & Online Reputation Management, growing the firm's LinkedIn following organically by 80% in 3 months
- ✓ Managed the overall external communications by effectively collaborating with our vendor partners to identify valuable media opportunities as well as external speaking assignments. Crafting and executing campaigns for the brand alongside proactively developing a brand guideline document and executing ad-hoc communication initiatives
- ✓ Led the content strategy for the newly launched reporting and communication platform for HNI clients

Edelweiss Gallagher Insurance Brokers, Mumbai

- Senior Manager Marketing | May 2021 to December 2021
- Manager- Marketing | May 2018 to May 2021
- Assistant Manager Marketing | December 2016 to May 2018
 - ✓ Directed a 8-member team across 2 locations to ideate, design and execute communication initiatives such as global quarterly newsletters, monthly newsletters, and other niche-specific communication initiatives
 - ✓ Handled external agency partners to ensure the timely inflow of deliverables.

- ✓ Launched Edelweiss Gallagher's social media handles with a social media strategy that garnered a 100% growth in followers and engagement within 24 months alongside
- ✓ Assisted the senior management with necessary market research
- ✓ Responsible for ORM and managing RFP repository for insurance tenders
- ✓ Was content lead for BlueBox- An insurance solutions digital platform developed for large corporate clients to provide elevated customer experience particularly in Auto & Commercial Insurance Sector

WNS Global Services, Mumbai

Assistant Manager - Global Marketing | May 2015 to December 2016

- ✓ Worked closely with the Strategic Marketing team to churn out internal communication strategies while spearheading the execution of over 100 external marketing campaigns in the Travel, Shipping & Logistics domain across European market.
- ✓ Worked closely with the sales team to build a pipeline of high quality MQL leads and manage sales pipeline for European sales leaders.
- ✓ Handled a portfolio of 45 clients and assisted vertical sales heads in account mining and database building and identifying business opportunities

Hexaware BPS, Mumbai

Sr Operations Specialist - Marketing | April 2014 to May 2015

✓ Managed 15 key accounts by profiling clients, building a database of 2500, drafting proposals and working closely with the bid management and presales team to develop solutions for clientele across BFSI industry vertical alongside coordinating with our agency partners for launch event arrangements and handling external communications

Other Experiences

Aqualogy, Alicante (Spain)

Marketing Intern | July 2013 to December 2013

The Nielsen Company, Mumbai

Survey Programmer | September 2011 to October 2012

Ugam Solutions, Thane

o Jr. Survey Programmer | April 2010 to September 2011

Skills

Budgeting | Corporate Communication | Campaign Planning & Execution | Content Creation | Email Marketing | Employer Branding | Internal Communication | Media Planning & Buying | Media Relations | Online Reputation Management | Performance Marketing | SEO & SEM | Social Media Strategy | Stakeholder Relationship Management | Event Planning | Webinar Development | Brand management | Digital Marketing |

Tools: Canva | CSS | Eloqua | Google Analytics | HTML | Java | Locobuzz | Microsoft Office | Netcore | Prezi | HubSpot

Education

Master of International Business Administration (IMBA)
Fundesem School of Business (Alicante – Spain) | 2012 to 2013

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc - IT) SIES College, Mumbai | 2005 to 2008

Certifications & Accreditations

Google Display Ads from Google | August 2021 Google Search Ads from Google | August 2021 OCP 9i